# **LUKE CASSADY-DORION**



# **Builder & Content Creator**

## luke@spstories.com

github.com/lukecd www.luke.gallery

### **PROFILE**

For the past 26 years, Luke has worked at the forefront of both technology and art. He wrote server-side Java and Java Applets in the 90s and 00s and during the web2 era, he launched a YouTube channel that grew to 650K subscribers and won awards for its commitment to social causes. He's worked as a software engineer, a CTO, a video editor, and film director. He's written books in English and Thai, and is just as comfortable writing code as he is editing video. He's at home on camera and excels at helping others feel comfortable and secure on screen.

He has taught yoga and Pilates for 20 years, both full and part-time. He has a strong background in education, having worked with thousands of students and having mentored multiple generations of new teachers.

His love of education and technology has perfectly positioned him for a career in DevRel. He is excited to leverage a life-long passion for technology with 20 years of teaching experience to help inspire a new generation of builders.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### A Single Production Company

"Co-Founder, Director" 2010 - 2020

- Directed award-winning feature documentary film "The Cheer Ambassadors".
- Directed "<u>D-Dance Dreams</u>", a 5-episode documentary series telling the story of a group of backup dancers as they prepare for a massive pop concert.
- Directed "<u>Yoga Namaste</u>", a 26-episode documentary series telling stories of people whose lives have changed by practicing yoga.
- Launched <u>Picnicly</u>, a YouTube channel dedicated to telling upbeat and inspirational stories, and grew to over 650,000 subscribers.
- With a large grant from <u>YouTube Global and the Creators For Change program</u>, launched a series of workshops to train a new generation of LGBTI+ YouTubers.
- Managed a full-time staff of 5 and teams of 20+ people on shoots.
- Built a website to directly engage our fans, thus ensuring changes to social media algorithms didn't impact our engagement.

## AbsoluteYou

"Senior Yoga And Pilates Instructor" 2004 - Present

- Helped grow a boutique fitness studio from 3 studios to 10, from 10 teachers to 100.
- Crafted written and video content to help train a geographically diverse staff.
- Launched a new social media team, leading to a 200% growth in Instagram and Facebook subscribers.
- Mentored new teachers, working one-on-one with them to develop their skills.
- Inspired students to lead happier, healthier lives.
- Taught hundreds of students daily, using individualized techniques designed to inspire each student.



#### Medem

"Co-Founder, CTO" 1999 - 2003

- Created a visual website builder tool to help physicians connect with their patients.
- Raised the quality of online healthcare information by building a one-click tool physicians use to share peer-reviewed content with their patients.
- Built HIPAA-compliant secure messaging system connecting physicians and patients.
- Helped define product specifications for a young, dynamic market.
- Researched new technologies and made build / buy decisions as we grew our platform.
- Traveled to healthcare conferences to educate physicians on our emerging platform.
- Managed a team of 10+ developers.

#### Metis LLC / Healtheon / WedMD

"Senior Software Engineer" 1997 - 1998

- Build screen-scraping tools to make legacy healthcare data available via a common interface.
- Designed and built a data integration system to merge backend data reporting systems.
- Crafted an API to publicize our data across different platforms. legacy healthcare reporting data accessible via a common API.
- Created a cross-platform Java client that both displayed and analyzed data from multiple sources.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Interdimensional One - Generative NFT-Based Art / Music Experience

https://interdimensional.one

- Coded Solidity smart contract to manage NFT minting.
- Created object-oriented JavaScript generative art plugin that interfaces with backend smart contracts.
- Created dApp frontend using React, Rainbow Kit and the WAGMI hooks.

## Adams Exchange - Decentralized Exchange Inspired By 42

https://adams.exchange

- Coded Solidity smart contracts to manage token creation, token swaps, token staking (with compound interest) and rewards claiming.
- Created innovative frontend animations using p5.js.
- Coded dApp frontend using React, Rainbow Kit and the WAGMI hooks.

# Web3 Voting - Winner Alchemy Road To Web 3 Hackathon

https://github.com/lukecd/team-dinamita-web3-voting

- Built Solidity smart contract to manage on-chain voting.
- Token-gated using a unique NFT whose on-chain design evolves after every vote, thus encouraging civic engagement.
- Worked with a global team as they integrated their frontend into my smart contracts.

#### **EDUCATION**



# Ramhamheang University - BA Thai Language Studies - 2007-2012

As a personal passion project, I returned to university to study Thai literature and language origins. After 4.5 years, I became the only Westerner to ever graduate from the university's strenuous program.

# **Drexel University - Computer Science - 1995-1997**

After two years, I dropped out to move to San Francisco and help start a healthcare technology company.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Yogi Boy: How I Learned To Breathe 2011 Author (Thai Language Book)
- Java Distributed Objects 1998 Co-author and primary editor
- Industrial Strength Java 1997 Co-author and primary editor
- JavaScript By Example 1996 Co-author